## **Kyle Schwartz**

kyle@kyleschwartz.ca (647) 772-7222 kyleschwartz.ca



#### To whom it may concern,

I am in my fourth year at the Lassonde School of Engineering, studying Computer Science. During my three years at university, I have broadened my computer knowledge to include JavaScript, Android, C/C++, Verilog, and Assembly. I also expanded my business acumen in studying micro and macro economics. I am excited to enhance my program with a coop opportunity where I can apply my learning in a practical environment.

During the school year, in addition to my studies, I also have a part time job teaching Minecraft to elementary-age students. I have enjoyed this opportunity as it allows me to share my passion with budding coders.

My last few summers I was a camp counsellor at Green Acres Day Camp where I honed my leadership ability. In my last placement I was recognized as the "staff of the summer" in my unit due to how I managed challenging camper behavioural issues by collaborating with the camp Social Worker to address the problem.

In my community, I sat on the Youth Board at Beth David Synagogue. In my first year I was the Vice President of Social Action & Charity where I organized several community events that were well received by the attendees. After successfully running for President, I continued to create, organize, and run engaging programs for the youth in my community. My role as President was to guide and oversee the Board and implement the strategic direction provided by our Youth Director.

In High School, I was active in the Computer Programming Team. During my time as a leader, I led a group of my peers in our school's coding competitions. We placed top 5 in multiple events. In addition, I was selected to be a coach for the visiting grade 7 & 8 students when they participated in our annual Science & Engineering Olympics.

I look forward to speaking with you about your coop program to determine if there is a fit with my skill set, strong work ethic, and leadership ability.

Sincerely,

#### **Kyle Schwartz**

# **Kyle Schwartz**





#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a hardworking and dedicated university student who loves computers in their entirety. Computers allow me to be creative, problem solve, and express myself in many facets including graphic and web design as well as coding. I am self-taught in Photoshop, Premiere Pro, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, and Microsoft Office Suite. Formally, I've learned Java, Adobe Animate, Android Development, and Turing. In my spare time, I decompress by cooking, woodworking, and rowing. I also love to travel around the world and experience different cultures.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Sanofi Pasteur

Toronto

University Internship Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

As a member of the Quality Control, Data Logistics and Support department, I assist my team in modernizing internal tools and improving workflows to maximize efficiency. Additionally, I document internal processes to ensure consistency and compliance in the future.

### Camp Green Acres

Markham

**Summer Camp Counsellor** Jun 2016 - Aug 2019

I worked as a staff member with young children ranging from 5 to 8 years of age in a fun, challenging, and supportive environment. In my second and third summers I was given the additional responsibility of being a bus captain; overseeing 3 staff members. This leadership experience afforded me the opportunity to understand team management and collaboration.

#### Grip Limited (now dentsu One) Toronto

**Cooperative Education Placement** Feb 2018 - May 2018

I worked in both the technology and video production departments, learning a great deal about corporate structure and how a business functions. I leveraged my knowledge of python to efficiently extract vendor data from excel workbooks, allowing for faster operations.

#### **AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Azure Al Fundamentals

Microsoft | Jun 2022

Earners of the Azure AI Fundamentals certification have demonstrated foundational knowledge of machine learning (ML) and artificial intelligence (AI) concepts and related Microsoft Azure services.

## **Fundamentals of Digital Marketing**

Google Digital Garage | Cert ID: MKC VS3 H3C | Oct 2018

## **Student Certificate of Achievement**

OCEA | May 2018

Awarded for individual success and participation in the Cooperative Education Program.

#### **Ontario Scholar**

TDSB | Jun 2018

Awarded for obtaining an average above eighty percent in any six Grade 12 courses.

## **Interactive Media Certificate**

FIT | Cert ID: 5766 | Jun 2018

## Software Design & Development

FIT | Cert ID: 5891 | Jun 2018

## **Excellence in Computer Science**

TDSB | Apr 2017

I received the top award for academic excellence in the field of computer science. As a result of this award, I was hand-selected to be placed in an advanced placement (AP) program for the 2017-2018 school year.

#### **PORTFOLIO**

#### Fossil 2

A self-hosted static file server for Docker built with Deno

#### svelte-spins ☑

A zero dependency spinner/loader library using loaders.css as Svelte components

#### ZoomCube ☑

A minimal Rubik's Cube timer written in Svelte

#### PDF Press ☑

Serverless PDF generator for Docusaurus and other SSGs

#### VSCStore ☑

A simple package to add the VSCode marketplace to VSCodium

#### 

A Snowpack plugin to convert YAML files to ESM

#### **EDUCATION**

## **High School Diploma**

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018 William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York

## **BSc Computer Science**,

#### **Minor in Economics**

Sep 2018 - Apr 2023 (Expected) Lassonde School of Engineering, York University, Toronto

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

#### **Youth Council President**

Beth David Synagogue, North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

After successfully running for President, I continued to create, organize, and run engaging programs for the youth in my community. My role as President was to guide and oversee my board and implement the strategic direction provided by our Youth Director.

### **President of Accounting & Finance Club**

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

I presented seminars on various forms of investment including cryptocurrencies and how to safely invest as markets can be very volatile.

## **Head Engineer for Engineering Club**

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

As an integral team member, I advised on the programming of our weekly activities to ensure the events were fun and informative for our members.

## **Computer Programming Team**

William Lyon Mackenzie C.I., North York Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

I led a group of my peers in our school's coding competitions. We placed top 5 in multiple events. In addition, I was selected to be a coach for the visiting grade 7 & 8 students when they participated in our annual Science & Engineering Olympics.